Guide to the Stanford Humanities Center Records
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford Humanities Center records
1982-2008
SC0876
Stanford Humanities Center.
15.5 Linear feet
The records pertain to administrative matters, including the Center's various homes, and its programs, including fellowships, lectures, and workshops. Materials include correspondence, memoranda, reports, proposals, publicity, and photographs. Audio-visual materials are cataloged under a separate call number (SC 827) and have their own finding aid.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
The Stanford Humanities Center, founded in 1980 by then-President Donald Kennedy, is dedicated to the advanced study of human history and culture. Humanities Center programs stress work of a multidisciplinary and collaborative nature. Now one of the most dynamic humanities centers in the country, the Stanford Humanities Center offers up to thirty-five fellowships every year, supports fifteen to twenty year-long research workshops, and stages numerous public events.
Description of the Collection
The records pertain to administrative matters, including the Center's various homes, and its programs, including fellowships, lectures, and workshops. Materials include correspondence, memoranda, reports, proposals, publicity, and photographs. Audio-visual materials are cataloged under a separate call number (SC 827) and have their own finding aid.
Access Terms
Stanford Humanities Center.; Humanities --Research.; Humanities--Study and teaching (Higher).
Collection Contents
- Records, Accesion ARCH-2007-237
  - History of SHC – administrative organization
    - Directors: (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Directors: Biographies (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Directors: Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Directors: Press (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Bylaws (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Committee members, 1983-2007 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - History of SHC – buildings & moves
    - Mariposa &Rogers houses: History 1984-93 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Mariposa &Rogers houses: Renovations 1985-96 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Mariposa &Rogers houses: Bible Sheets 1990 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Mariposa &Rogers houses: Room M-20 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Mariposa &Rogers houses: IWP (Infrastructure Wiring Project) 1999 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Mariposa &Rogers houses: Furniture Upgrades (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Mariposa &Rogers houses: ADA Compliance 1996-99 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Mariposa &Rogers houses: Press 1999 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Annex: Administration 1992-97 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Annex: Furniture Upgrade 1988 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Annex: Space Requests 1998-99 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Bowman house: Building Administration 2000-01 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Bowman house: Artist's sketch (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - History of SHC – Operations
    - Staff Handbook (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Facilities: ABM Definitions & Schedules (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Facilities: Work Orders (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Facilities: Building Security (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Computing Services 1995-2000 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - External Computing Guides (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Internal Computing Guides 1996 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Computer Budget 1996-97 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Equipment 1986-99 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Early Website (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Y2K (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Lunches: Menus & feedback (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Publicity & Public Relations
    - Press releases and clippings, 1988-2003 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - News articles of events (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Annual Reports: 1989 – 2006 (Box 3)
    - Newsletters 1995-2001 (incomplete set) (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Campaign Materials (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Stanford Humanities Review
    - General records 1999-2000 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Accounts (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Fellowship Programs
    - Publicity 2006-07 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - List of Fellows 1995-2006 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Fellowship Statistics 1982-96 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Review Guidelines 1987-2001 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Review Guidelines (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous: Stipends 1999-2000 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous: Offices 1999 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous: SHC activities 1998-99 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Publications (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Fellows' Manuals 1999-2006 (Box 3)
    - Fellows CVs and Project Descriptions (1) (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Fellows CVs and Project Descriptions (2) (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Fellows CVs and Project Descriptions (3) (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Fellows CVs and Project Descriptions (4) (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Fellows CVs and Project Descriptions (5) (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - External Faculty Fellowship: publicity (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Internal Faculty Fellowship: Publicity (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Internal Faculty Fellowship: Sabbatical leave policy (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - HIS [Humanities and International Studies] Fellowship: Publicity (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Associate Fellowship: Publicity (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Rockefeller Fellowship: Publicity (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Rockefeller Fellowship: Grant Information (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Digital Humanities Fellowship: publicity (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Dean Fellows (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Shared Research Group: publicity (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Graduate Fellowship: Publicity (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Graduate Fellowship: Pre-Doctoral (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Graduate Fellowship: Geballe (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Undergraduate Fellowship: Publicity (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Undergraduate Fellowship: Grant Proposal (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Undergraduate Fellowship: Grant Accounting (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Major Events
    - Conferences (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Camp Lectures (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Carnochan Lectures (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Miscellaneous Lectures (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Presidential Lectures (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Weeks Lectures (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - West Lectures (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Miscellaneous Events (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Research Workshops
    - Correspondence (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Funding History (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - NEH Application 2004 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Administrative Guide, version 1, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Administrative Guide, version 2, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Coordinator's Manual, 2000-01 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Coordinator's Manual, 2001-02 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Coordinator's Manual, 2002-03 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Coordinator's Manual, 2003-04 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Coordinator's Manual, 2004-05 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Coordinator's Manual, 2005-06 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Coordinator's Manual, 2006-07 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Workshop Sample Proposals (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Workshop Proposals 2003-04: general memos, etc. (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Workshop Proposals 2003-04: New (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Workshop Proposals 2003-04: Renewal (1 of 2) (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Workshop Proposals 2003-04: Renewal (2 of 2) (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Workshop Proposals 2004-05 (1 of 2) (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Workshop Proposals 2004-05 (2 of 2) (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Workshop Proposals 2005-06 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Workshop Proposals 2006-07 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Workshop evaluations 2001-02 (1 of 2) (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Workshop evaluations 2001-02 (2 of 2) (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Workshop End of Year Reports 2001-02 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Workshops 2003-04 Financials: Sept.-Nov. (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Workshops 2003-04 Financials: Dec.-April (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Workshops 2003-04 Financials: May-August (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Workshops 2003-04 Evaluations (1 of 2) (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Workshops 2003-04 Evaluations (2 of 2) (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Workshops 2003-04 End of Year Reports (1 of 2) (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Workshops 2003-04 End of Year Reports (2 of 2) (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Workshops 2004-05 Evaluations (1 of 3) (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Workshops 2004-05 Evaluations (2 of 3) (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Workshops 2004-05 Evaluations (3 of 3) (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Workshops 2004-05 End of Year Reports (1 of 2) (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Workshops 2004-05 End of Year Reports (2 of 2) (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Photographs (includes prints, negatives, and digital scans): (Box 9)
  - 1) Building, including a series of images by Jane Lidz (Box 9)
  - 2) Events: Conferences, Distinguished Visiting Fellows, Camp Lecture, Presidential Lecture, Weeks Lecture, West Lecture, and miscellaneous (Box 9)
  - 3) Fellows and Staff, 1993-2007 (Box 9)
  - 4) Miscellaneous: Former Directors, Major Donors (Box 9)
  - Set of slides of text of poems (author not noted), Nov. 1999 (Box 9)
  - Posters from Presidential Lectures, Bliss Carnochan Lectures, Weeks Lectures, West Lectures, Camp Lectures, conferences (including the SHC's 25th Anniversary), co-sponsored events, and others, 2001-07 (Box 10)
- Additional material, Accesion ARCH-2007-335
  - Materials pertaining to renovation of the Bowman Alumni building to house the Stanford Humanities Center
    - Eames furniture brochure 2001 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 40/4 wood furniture (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Davis furniture brochures 1998 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - GF office furniture, Vol. III seating (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Room & Board Catalog [furniture company] 2000 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Bowman Hall Programming and Space Allocation Study, draft January 2000 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Vitra Standards [chair catalog] 2001 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Chair catalogs (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Seaside Graphics The Complete Tint book (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Full Upright Position, the modern furniture company, No. 5 [catalog] (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Floor/room/piece adhesives (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Illustration of interior 2001 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Magnified layout drawings with corresponding photos (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Photographs (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Photographs (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Photographs (incl. negatives) (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Photographs (incl. negatives) (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Oversize architectural drawings, renderings, etc., Meeks, Coates & Eaton Architects, and some photographs, 2000-01 (Box 2 os)
- Additional material, Accession ARCH-2014-091
  - Colon, David A. Application for PWR, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Colon, David A. Teaching Portfolio, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Anderson, Stacey Teaching Portfolio, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Anderson, Stacey, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Lee, Sohui Teaching Portfolio, 11/1/2004 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Marconi, Melissa, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Kelso, Josephine, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Roman, Laura, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Webb, Rebecca, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Willihnganz, Jonah, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Willihnganz, Jonah Evals, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Wyle, Susan, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Straley, Jessica, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Magrath, Katie paper, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Wyle, Susan rehire, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Wyle, Susan CV, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Census 2000 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Census 2000 prepared by Katya Seryakova, 6/8/2001 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Census 2000 marketing question, 5/18/2001 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Polarization of American Parties, 1/27/2004 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Census 2000 Analysis Ken Prewitt and Documents, 11/1/2002 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - The study survey 2001 time study analysis, 7/18/2001 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Stanford Institute for Quantitative Study of Society, 10/26/2006 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Agenda book workshop on measurement of and research on time use, 1999 27-28 May (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Socrates an introduction to Stanford's online catalog, guidebooks to Stanford, 1997-1998 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Knowledge Networks study/survey, 4/28/2004 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Stanford SIQSS Time Budget 2003, 4/22/2003 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Bio Building, 2000-2003 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Bio Building Planning - 2006 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Building 1, 2002-2004 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Building 500, 2003-2004 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Capital Plan FY 09, 2007 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Capital Plan 2007-2008 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Capital Plan FY 07, 2005-2007 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Capital Plan FY 05, 2004-2005 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Capital Plan FY 04, 2003-2004 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Capital Plan 2002, 2001-2002 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Capital Planning Management, 2002-2003 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Chem Stores, 2001-2002 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Clark Center (see Bio-X file), undated (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Electricity Use Reports, 2002-2003 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Emergency Preparedness, 2000-2003 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - IHUM, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Reframing Area One Elam and Ross, undated (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Bulletin 01-02, 2001-2002 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Stanford Institute for Creativity and the Arts, 5/17/2007 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - The Proposal: Comparitive Design Process/Use of Parametics in Architecture and Product Design, 2007-2008 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Nanocenter Project, 2007 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Ecina Space Plannign Study, 2005-2006 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Facilities Reserve, 2002-2003 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Facilities Budget, 2005-2006 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Jasper Ridges, 2005-2007 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Jordan Hall Renovation, 2002-2003 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Kavli Institute, 2003-2004 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Lab Space Guidelines, 2007 April-May (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Land and Buildings, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - iSpace, 2003 Dec. (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Nova: Flood! (About the 1993 Miss. River Flood), 1996; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Gilbane Gold A Case Study in Engineering Ethics Produced by NSPE's National Institute for Engineering Ethics, 1989; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Ethics in Business, undated; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - "The Great Chicago Flood of 1992" segment of "The New Explorers", 1993; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Nova - "Why Planes Burn" "The Education Race" Americans in Japanese-owned U.S. Business, undated; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Brooklyn Bridge, undated; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Toscanini: The Maestro, undated; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - IDEO Product Development ABC Nightline "IDEO - The Deep Dive", 2/9/1999; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - New Explorers Series: Great Chicago Flood, undated; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Engineering Education, 1994; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Nova: "Do Scientists Cheat", 10/25/1988; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Award Winning Teachers on Teaching Professor Robert McGinn (STS) "Cultivating the Capability for Rigorous Critical Analysis...", 1/22/1998; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - The Machine that Changed the World, undated; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - SIQSS Stanford Study Takes First Look at How Internet is Changing Daily Life, undated; 1 videotape(s) (Betacam-SP) (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - SIQSS Stanford Study Takes First Look at How Internet is Changing Daily Life, undated; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Benefactor, 2001-2006 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Cantor, 2001-2005 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - C [Cue (Campaign for Undergraduate Education)], 2002 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Center for Comparative Studies in Race and Ethnicity, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Division of Literatures, Cultures, and Languages, 2006 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - E [Endowed Professorships and Directorships and School of Engineering], 2000-2003 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - G [Graduate School of Business], 2001-2005 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - L [Law school, Lively Arts], 2003-2005 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - M [Medical Center], 2001-2006 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - N [Nordstrom], 2003 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - P [Parents' Program], 2001-2002 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Q [empty], undated (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - R [Reunion Homecoming], 2003-2006 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Stanford Graduate Fellowships in Science and Engineering, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Stanford Annual Report, 2002-2003 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Faculty & Resource Guide, 2000-2001 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Stanford Drama, 2006-2007 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Communication Policy in Comparative Perspective, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Academic History, 2002-2006 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Draft Papers: Appointment Professor (Research) and Senior Fellow, 10/2/2006 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Stanford Introductory Seminars Course Catalog, 2006-2007 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - STS 101: Lecture #15, 11/11/2006 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - STS 101: Lecture #15, 11/11/2006 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - STS 101: Lecture #15, 11/11/2006 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - STS 101: Lecture #15, 11/11/2006 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - STS 101: Lecture #15, 11/11/2006 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - STS 101: Lecture #15, 11/11/2006 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - STS 101: Lecture #15, 11/11/2006 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - STS 101: Lecture #15, 11/11/2006 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - STS 101: Lecture #15, 11/11/2006 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - STS 101: Lecture #15, 11/11/2006 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - STS 101: Lecture #15, 11/11/2006 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - STS 101: Lecture #15, 11/11/2006 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - STS 101: Lecture #15, 11/11/2006 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - STS 101: Lecture #15, 11/11/2006 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - STS 101: Lecture #15, 11/11/2006 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - STS 101: Lecture #15, 11/11/2006 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - STS 101: Lecture #15, 11/11/2006 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - STS 101: Lecture #15, 11/11/2006 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - STS 101: Lecture #15, 11/11/2006 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - STS 101: Lecture #15, 11/11/2006 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - STS 101: Lecture #15, 11/11/2006 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - STS 101: Lecture #15, 11/11/2006 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - STS 101: Lecture #15, 11/11/2006 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - STS 101: Lecture #15, 11/11/2006 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Ten Postmanesque Theses re Technology, Science, and Comtemporary Ideational Culture (Multiple Copies) - Loose Papers, Undated (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Majoring in STS: Some Questions and Answers - loose papers divided, Undated (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Close-out documents, circa 2008 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - The Workcenter After Grotowski - Loose paper, 10/13/2006 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Spec Sheets for Bldg 120 - Loose papers pp 1-8, 1/2/2008 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Stanford Bldg. 01-120 Close Out Binder, 2007 (Box 6, Folder 35)